MARSHALL MILEY

Golden, CO

Phone: 601-594-6591 | Email: mrmileyy@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mileymarshall/ GitHub: https://github.com/m-miley

Summary

Enthusiastic Data Analyst with a strong background in mathematics and a passion for accuracy, aptitude for clear communication, penchant for solving complex problems, and drive for developing actionable insights to cultivate success. Talent for converting complex data into palatable stories.

Technical Skills

Excel - Pivot Tables, Visualizations, Analysis, VBA Scripting
SQL - PostgreSQL, SQLite, SQLAlchemy, pgAdmin 4, Quick DBD
Tableau - Dashboards and Stories
Python - Pandas, Matplotlib, Flask, NumPy, API interactions, Jupyter Notebook
Statistics & Modeling - Descriptive, Inferential, Regression
GitHub - repositories, commits, pulls

Projects

Airbnb | https://github.com/markm3690/AirbnbAshevilleNC

Cleaned and analyzed web-scraped data using the Data Analysis workflow for current prices, listing size, capacity, location, host data, etc to extract insights and communicate a basic pricing structure for new hosts to kickstart and update existing listings. Excel, PowerPoint Presentation.

Lyft – Bay Wheels | https://github.com/markm3690/Baywheels_SF

Queried SQL database to analyze data from ~5million rides spanning 2.5 years to present suggestions for distribution, maintenance, and bike models based on user type, trip length, dock capacity, and frequency of travel. PostgreSQL, pgAdmin 4, Excel, PowerPoint Presentation.

NASS Honey Bees | https://public.tableau.com/app/profile/marshall3619/viz/NASSHoneyBees/HoneyBee With Tableau, I built and published an analysis from a Honey Bee data set provided by NASS. Implemented detailed data visualization strategies to create two interactive dashboards tracking health and economy. Culminated in a 10 minute peer presentation using Story mode in Tableau.

Education

University of Denver Denver, CO

2022

Data Analytics & Visualization Boot Camp Certificate

24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, Web Scraping, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning.

General Assembly London, UK

2022

Data Analytics Certificate

10-week program focused on completing thorough analysis on a range of data sets from superstore to rideshare, government, and science. Skills in Excel, SQL, Tableau

L'institut de Touraine Tours, France

2010

French Language Study

Immersive and Intensive 8-week study of French Language and culture.

Mississippi College Clinton, MS.

2008

B.S. Mathematics

Emphasis on complex problem solving and applied mathematics. Calculus I-IV, statistics, modern geometry, topology, linear algebra, discrete mathematics, modern algebra, differential equations, trigonometry, physics, chemistry. Business minor. Cum Laude, Honors, Pi Mu Epsilon.

Experience

Assistant Store Manager

2017-2022

Natural Grocers by Vitamin Cottage Golden, CO

Manage a crew of 34 employees to meet monthly sales projection. Persistent, proactive, and daily strive for operational excellence. Boost morale through daily huddles and monthly meetings to maximize employee retention, job satisfaction, and efficiency. Focus and drive to accomplish sales goals, meet deadlines, merchandise product, and display promotional materials effectively. Scheduling, Recruiting, Leadership, Training, Mentoring, HR Best Practices, Conflict Resolution, Conference calls, Sales calls, Inventory Management, QRG's and much more! +9-30% produce sales comp, +4-8% store sales comp through merchandising, accurate ordering, and world class CS.

Garden Manager 2016-2017

Harmony Gardens Golden, CO

Successful full season growth and propagation for organic fruit and vegetables. Engineered irrigation systems and crop layout designs. Organic composting, fertilizing, and pest management best practices lead to abundant and delicious produce. Harvesting, communication, and distribution of yield. Promote community involvement and hype. Focus on building healthy soil.

LTP Trail Crew Leader 2014-2015

Green Mountain Club Waterbury Center, VT

Build and maintain Vermont trail systems. Manage food/team/supplies. Lead volunteer crews on spike camps, 4 nights/5 days a week. Cut 5+ miles new trail including 1 mile linking AT to LT. Paint AT boundary, 40 step rock staircase in wilderness area. Promote enjoyment and work satisfaction.

Lead Technician 2012-2014

Polaris Laboratories Salt Lake City, Utah

Lead night crew to test and analyze oil samples according to rigorous scientific testing. ICP-AES, Acid/Base titrations, Viscosity, Particle Count, Particle Quantifier, Brix, etc. Through managing time and troubleshooting equipment, I ensured the team met test quota while confirming accuracy.

References

Available Upon Request